Guide to the Engin Ozendes Collection of Ottoman photography AD.MC.012
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
- Bosphorus strait with views of Maiden's Tower, Ayazma Mosque, and Rum Mehmed Pasha Mosque. A man in a rowboat is in the foreground. 23.2 x 31.2 cm, Undated; 3840; Berggren, Guillaume (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Bosphorus; Maiden's Tower; Buildings; Ports; Ayazma Mosque; Rum Mehmed Pasha Mosque; French Writing; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Boats/Ships; Water; Architecture; Lighthouses; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Religious Sites
- Golden Gate and Yedikule Fortress. Identical print to ref 134. 24.5 x 29.6 cm, 1898; 3845; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; French Writing; Golden Gate, Jerusalem; Buildings
- View of Cannon battery in a fort across the Bosphorus strait from Yoros Castle and Anadolu Kavagi, Istanbul. French writing on front: "Vue de la batterie de Madjian Kalé et d'Anatol Kavak." 23.2 x 31.5 cm, Undated; 3848; Berggren, Guillaume (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Water; Men; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Cannons; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Bosphorus; Forts/Castles; Anadolu Kavagi, Istanbul, Turkey; French Writing; Weapons
- Grand Mosque of Bursa (Ulucami), Bursa. 19 x 25 cm, 1880; 3855; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Architecture; Bursa, Turkey; Mosques; Albumen Prints; Fountains; Religious Sites; Arabic Writing; Fountains; Carpets/Rugs; Boys; Men; Photographic Prints; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Grand Mosque of Bursa; Group Portraits
- Porte de Tripoli, Syrie. Port of Tripoli, modern day Lebanon. 20 x 26 cm, Undated; 3856; Bonfils, Felix (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Boats/Ships; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Ports; Syria; Lebanon; Mediterranean Sea; Water; Buildings
- Tomb in Eyup. Tomb of Abu Ayyub al-Ansari. Courtyard of Eyup Sultan Mosque, Istanbul, Turkey. 20 x 26 cm, 1870; 3857; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Religious Sites; Hats; Men; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Streets/Roads; Eyup Sultan Mosque; Mosques; Eyup, Istanbul, Turkey; Outdoors; Istanbul, Turkey; French Writing; Architecture
- View of Heybeliada from Buyukada. 20 x 26 cm, 1890; 3858; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Sea of Marmara; Seas; Water; Prince Islands, Istanbul, Turkey; Buyukada, Istanbul, Turkey
- Mirahor Palace at Kagithane, Istanbul, Turkey. 20 x 26 cm, 1894; 3859; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Boats/Ships; Rivers; Mirahor Palace; Constantinople; Kagithane, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Buildings; Outdoors; Umbrellas/Parasols; Palaces
- Ottoman troops at Wadi Halfa, Sudan. 20 x 26 cm, Undated; 3860; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Weapons; Camels; Horses; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Guns; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Sudan; Military/Soldiers; Men; Wadi Halfa, Sudan; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Animals; Group Portraits
- Friday procession to Yildiz Mosque, Yildiz Palace in the background to the left. 19 x 25 cm, 1880; 3861; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Constantinople; Mosques; Yildiz Hamidiye Mosque; Besiktas, Istanbul, Turkey; Guns; Religious Sites; Military/Soldiers; Fezes/Tarbouches; Hats; Carriages/Coaches; Architecture; Weapons; Buildings; Palaces; Group Portraits
- Nubian warriors, "soldiers of the Khedive," awaiting the arrival of the Sultan's "Khedive" (Governor of Egypt and Sudan) 77A. 20 x 26 cm, Undated; 3862; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Albumen Prints; Armor; Photographic Prints; Military/Soldiers; Regional/National Dress; Buildings; Sudan; Flags; Weapons; Swords/Knives; Camels; Egypt; Men; Animals; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- Buildings and gardens within the Fortress of Seven Towers, or the Yedikule Fortress. 20.7 x 26.7 cm, 1890; 3863; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Constantinople; Photographic Prints; Forts/Castles; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Istanbul, Turkey
- Buildings and mountains in Bursa. 20.7 x 26.8 cm, 1894; 3864; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Houses; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Mountains/Hills; Buildings; Bursa, Turkey
- Cattle in a river next to a road in Bursa, Turkey. 20.8 x26.9 cm, 1894; 3865; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Cattle/Cows; Rivers; Animals; Bursa, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Children; Boys; Bridges; Outdoors; Streets/Roads
- Tomb of Sultan Murad II in the Muradiye Complex, Bursa, Turkey. 20.8 x 26.6 cm, 1894; 3866; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Fountains; Children; Boys; Religious Sites; Bursa, Turkey; Tombs; Constantinople; Individual Portraits
- Door of Yesil (Green) Mosque, or Mosque of Mehmed I, Bursa, Turkey. 26.7 x 20.8 cm, 1894; 3867; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Architecture; Doors/Entrances; Men; Mosques; Green Mosque, Bursa; Bursa, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Arabic Writing; Religious Sites; Individual Portraits
- Rooftops of Bursa with numerous mosques visible including the Grand Mosque of Bursa in the center-left of the image. 20.9 x 26.2 cm, 1894; 3874; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Boys; Architecture; Grand Mosque of Bursa; Bursa, Turkey; Children; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Mountains/Hills; Mosques; Religious Sites
- Countryside in Bursa, facing north from behind Hudavendigar Mosque (in the foreground). 20.7 x 26.8 cm, 1894; 3875; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  French Writing; Landscapes; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Hudavendigar Mosque; Bursa, Turkey; Countryside/Rural; Architecture; Religious Sites
- Galata Tower, Istanbul. 26.6 x 20.6 cm, 1889; 3876; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Streets/Roads; Buildings; Architecture; Istanbul, Turkey; Galata Tower; Constantinople; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Flags
- Three boys and a man standing in front of the door of Yesil (Green) Mosque, or Mosque of Mehmed I, Bursa, Turkey. 26.8 x 20.9 cm, 1894; 3877; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Architecture; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Green Mosque, Bursa; Bursa, Turkey; Mosques; Doors/Entrances; Hats; Men; Children; Boys; Arabic Writing; Religious Sites; Children; Boys; Group Portraits
- The Golden Horn, Istanbul, taken from the Eyup Cemetery. 21 x 26.9 cm, 1900; 3878; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Boats/Ships; Architecture; Water; Constantinople; Rivers; Eyup, Istanbul, Turkey; The Golden Horn/Haliç
- Abide-i Hurriyet, Monument of Liberty, Sisli, Istanbul, Turkey. 26.8 x 20.8 cm, 1900; 3879; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Monument of Liberty; Architecture; Doors/Entrances; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Sisli, Istanbul, Turkey; Monuments/Memorials
- Haydarpasa Ingiliz Mezarligi (British Cemetery), Crimean War Memorial, Haidar Pasha Cemetery, Uskudar, Istanbul. 26.9 x 20.9 cm, 1900; 3880; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Cemeteries; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Monuments/Memorials; Uskudar, Istanbul, Turkey; French Writing
- Yildiz Palace, Istanbul, Turkey. 20.7 x 26.7 cm, 1900; 3881; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Yildiz Palace; Albumen Prints; Outdoors; Buildings; Architecture; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Palaces
- Golden Gate, Yedikule, Istanbul. Identical print to ref 111. 20.8 x 26.8 cm, 1898; 3882; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Architecture; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Forts/Castles; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; French Writing; Buildings
- Kucuksu Pavilion (formerly Goksu Pavilion) and the Mihrisah Valide Sultan Fountain (also Kucuksu Fountain). 19.8 x 26.5 cm, 1900; 3883; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Buildings; Architecture; Fountains; Kucuksu Palace; Outdoors; Rivers; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Bosphorus; Palaces; Kiosks/Kushk
- Entrance to the Black Sea from the Bosphorus. 20.8 x 26.8 cm, 1890; 3884; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Seas; Istanbul, Turkey; Rivers; Water; Bosphorus; Black Sea
- Galata Tower, Istanbul, Turkey. 24.6 x 18.1 cm, Circa 1900; 3885; Iranian, Mihran, Active circa 1890-1900 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Flags; Constantinople; Buildings; Architecture; Albumen Prints; Galata Tower; Photographic Prints; Istanbul, Turkey
- Galata Tower, Istanbul, Turkey. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated; 3886; Iranian, Mihran, Active circa 1890-1900 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Outdoors; Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Galata Tower; Flags; Constantinople; Buildings; Architecture; Albumen Prints
- Woman wearing pearls and a veil with a dark shawl, holding a hand fan. 25.2 x 18.6 cm, Undated; 3889; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Hand Fans; Jewelry; Women; Constantinople; Photographic Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Head Covers/Veils
- Woman standing in a dress, arms akimbo, with a shisha. 23.5 x 19.5 cm, Undated; 3890; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Constantinople; Hats; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Embroidery; Jewelry; Smoking; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Women
- Woman wearing pearls, a veil, and a dark shawl holding a hand fan trimmed with feathers. 23.8 x 18.4 cm, Circa 1880; 3891; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Women; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Jewelry; Furnishings; Hand Fans; Head Covers/Veils; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints
- Men washing before prayer at ablution fountains at the Suleymaniye Mosque in Istanbul, Turkey. 18.5 x 25.5 cm, Circa 1890; 3892; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Religious Sites; Religious Ceremony; Men; Mosques; Fountains; Suleymaniye Mosque; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- Ceremony at Yildiz Palace, Istanbul, Turkey. 19.4 x 24.9 cm, 1898; 3893; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Streets/Roads; Hats; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Military/Soldiers; Architecture; Flags; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Yildiz Palace; Men; Palaces; Group Portraits
- The Battlefields of Toski, near Abu Simbel, Egypt. 20.2 x 26.3 cm, Undated; 3894; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Toski, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Military/Soldiers; Wars; Men; Deserts; Landscapes
- Mihrisah Valide Sultan Fountain (also Kucuksu Fountain, Asia Freshwater Fountain), a shepherd with six sheep, and a street vendor selling food. 19.1 x 25.1 cm, Undated; 3895; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Fountains; Water; Hats; Street Vendors; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Constantinople; Food; Istanbul, Turkey; Animals; Outdoors; Kucuksu Palace; Bosphorus; Palaces; Sheep; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Fezes/Tarbouches
- Two ferries arriving at a port on a river in Egypt. 20.1 x 26.2 cm, Undated; 3896; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Flags; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Egypt; Lakes; Rivers; Boats/Ships; Water; Boats/Ships; Nile River
- Steamboats traveling on the Nile River. Voyage of Sultan Abdulaziz. 20.1 x 26.2 cm, Undated; 3897; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Egypt; Water; Lakes; Rivers; Nile River; Boats/Ships; Boats/Ships; Flags; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints
- Walls of the Yedikule Fortress, Istanbul, Turkey. 19.5 x 25.4 cm, Circa 1880; 3898; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Outdoors; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Forts/Castles; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Buildings
- Prince Yusuf Izzettin Efendi (1857-1916) as a boy, during his visit to Egypt. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, Undated; 3899; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Swords/Knives; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Uniforms; Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Weapons; Boys; Children; Royalty
- Prince Mehmed Seyfeddin Efendi (1874-1927) as a young boy, standing with a sword. 16.3 x 11.2 cm, Undated; 3900; Studio B. Kargopoulo & Foscolo, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Studio Photography; Boys; Children; Uniforms; Swords/Knives; Fezes/Tarbouches; Hats; Furnishings; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Carpets/Rugs; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Weapons; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Royalty
- "Sifahiye" (hospital) doorway to the Gevher Nesibe complex, Antalya, Turkey. 18 x 12.9 cm, 1945; 3901; Tolgay, Hayri T. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Antalya, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Doors/Entrances; Buildings; Turkish Writing; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Gevher Nesibe Hospital Complex
- President Mustafa Kemal Ataturk (1881-1938) and, on the right, Prime Minister Ismet Pasha (1884-1973) introducing the new turkish alphabet in Kayseri, Anatolia, Turkey (linked ref155). 9.1 x 14 cm, 20 September 1928; 3902; Tolgay, Hayri T. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Smoking; Mustafa Kemal Ataturk, 1881-1938; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Pasha, Ismet; Turkish Writing; Men; Anatolia, Turkey; Uniforms; Pasha; Kayseri,Turkey; Political Leadership; Group Portraits; Police; Facial Hair; Cigarettes; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
- Turkish Prime Minister Ismet Pasha giving a speech at a ceremony for the opening of rail service to Kayseri, Turkey. 11.4 x 17.1 cm, 29 May 1927; 3903; Tolgay, Hayri T. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Pasha, Ismet; Kayseri,Turkey; Hats; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing; Speeches; Flags; Ceremonies; Group Portraits; Transportation; Railways; Ottoman Writing; Crowds; Audiences/Spectators
- Panorama of Kayseri. The clock tower, Grand Bazaar and Kayseri Castle. 9.9 x 17 cm, 1927; 3904; Tolgay, Hayri T. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Grand Bazaar; Gelatin Silver Prints; Kayseri,Turkey; Landscapes; Forts/Castles; Architecture; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing; Clocks/Watches
- President Mustafa Kemal Ataturk (1881-1938) and, on the right, Prime Minister Ismet Pasha (1884-1973) introducing the new Turkish alphabet in Kayseri (linked ref152). 17 x 12.3 cm, 20 September 1928; 3905; Tolgay, Hayri T. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Hats; Uniforms; Smoking; Pasha, Ismet; Mustafa Kemal Ataturk, 1881-1938; Kayseri,Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Turkish Writing; Men; Political Leadership; Group Portraits; Police; Facial Hair; Cigarettes; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
- Children at Haci Mansur Primary School in Kayseri, Turkey celebrating Republic Day with banners and traditional Turkish dress. 11.9 x 17.1 cm, 29 October 1932; 3906; Tolgay, Hayri T. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Hats; Buildings; Regional/National Dress; Schools/Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Kayseri,Turkey; Ceremonies; Girls; Boys; Children; Parades/Processions; Uniforms; Group Portraits
- Self-portrait of photographer Hayri T. Tolgay. 18 x 12.9 cm, Circa 1950; 3907; Tolgay, Hayri T. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Individual Portraits; Men; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Turkey; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair
- Street vendors from Port Said, Egypt. Two boys sitting and one girl standing, the girl carrying produce on her head and the boys with vegetables in a basket in front of them. On reverse side of ref159. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; 3908; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Fezes/Tarbouches; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Hats; Albumen Prints; Street Vendors; Boys; Women; Children; Port Said, Egypt; Group Portraits; Food; Head Covers/Veils
- Woman sitting on a studio boulder fixture, holding a piece of pottery, leaning on a wide-bottomed amphora. On reverse side of ref158. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; 3909; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Pottery; Women; Egypt; Painted Backdrops
- Woman reclined on a pillow, holding a hand fan with a tall pipe at her feet. French writing at the bottom: "Arab woman having her siesta in a villa near the Pyramides." 19.9 x 26.8 cm, Undated; 3910; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  French Writing; Hand Fans; Egypt; Women; Jewelry; Albumen Prints; Painted Backdrops; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Hats; Smoking; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles
- Hand-colored photograph of a man in a suit standing on the bank of a creek in the woods. 16.6 x 12.5 cm, Undated; 3911; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Paintings; Turkey; Outdoors; Water; Rivers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Individual Portraits
- Tomb with intricately carved wood panels. 23.6 x 31 cm, Undated; 3912; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Arabic Writing; Tombs; Furnishings; Architecture; Arabic Calligraphy; Turkey; Photographic Prints; Coffins/Caskets; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Sites
- Three women and a young boy standing under a tree on the banks of the Nilufer River, Gecit Korusu, Bursa, Turkey. 30 x 25 cm, 1929; 3913; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Water; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Bursa, Turkey; Hats; Boys; Children; Turkish Writing; Women; Rivers; Outdoors; Group Portraits
- A man and woman standing under a tree on the Nilufer River with a stone bridge in the background, Gecit Korusu, Bursa, Turkey. 30 x 24.9 cm, 1908; 3914; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Bursa, Turkey; Hats; Women; Men; Bridges; Rivers; Outdoors; Turkish Writing; Water; Photographic Prints
- Three women, a man and a boy standing under the Nilufer Bridge, spanning the Nilufer River in Bursa, Turkey. Identified on the label as one of the first Turkish architectural monuments in Bursa. 23.4 x 29.8 cm, Undated; 3915; Studio Foto Hilal, Bakirkoy, Istanbul Cad Cavusoglu pasaji 9 (Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Turkish Writing; Bridges; Bursa, Turkey; Men; Women; Children; Boys; Hats; Water; Rivers; Outdoors; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
- Self-portrait of Arif Hikmet Koyunoglu standing in front of the State Art and Sculpture Museum in Ankara, Turkey. 31 x 22.8 cm, Undated; 3916; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Men; Ankara, Turkey; State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Buildings; Architecture; Museums
- Green Mosque in Bursa, Turkey, in the snow. 23 x 17 cm, Undated; 3917; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Bursa, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Snow; Architecture; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Mosques; Green Mosque, Bursa; Religious Sites
- Street cobbler in Eyup. 17.9 x 22.7 cm, 1905; 3918; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Turbans; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Doors/Entrances; Street Vendors; Eyup, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Hats; Workers
- A Street in Bursa. 23.8 x 18.2 cm, 1908; 3919; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Docks/Piers/Jetties; Doors/Entrances; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Houses; Buildings; Bursa, Turkey
- Eight soldiers of the Ottoman army ski association on the Caucasian front. 17.8 x 24 cm, 1913; 3920; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  World War I; Wars; Group Portraits; Animals; Snow Skis; Uniforms; Turkey; Snow; Dogs; Hats; Men; Caucasus; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair
- Carved wood minbar from a Turkish mosque. 31 x 23.3 cm, Undated; 3921; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Architecture; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Turkey; Religious Sites; Mosques
- Man standing with large decorated tile. 30 x 23.2 cm, Undated; 3922; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Men; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Turkey; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches
- Arabic script carved into wood panels. 30 x 23.2 cm, Undated; 3923; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Architecture; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mosques; Furnishings; Arabic Calligraphy; Art; Arabic Writing; Religious Sites
- State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara, Turkey, under construction. 22.8 x 31 cm, Undated; 3924; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Buildings; Museums; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Construction; State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara; Ankara, Turkey; Architecture
- Hand-colored photograph of Yeni Kaplica ("new spa") thermal bath, Bursa, Turkey. 23 x 31 cm, Undated; 3925; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Architecture; Buildings; Bursa, Turkey
- Theater hall inside the State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara, Turkey. 23 x 31 cm, Undated; 3926; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)